二零二零年河南省普通高中
招生考试英语。
一、听力理解。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
,B 1. me, how can I find the book called The Most Dangerous Game?
三个选项中选出。
最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
Oh, I'm afraid it was sold out.
Excuse me, how can I find the book called The Dangerous Game?
2. Where do you live,
I live on Baker Street in a really tall modern building.
It has 20 floors.
I live on the second.
And there is a fitness center on the
Where do you live, Carol?
I live on Baker Street in a really tall modern building.
It has 20 floors.
I live on the second.
And there is a fitness center on the seventh.
3. What do you want to do this weekend?
Let's go shopping and then get a coffee.
You know, I hate shopping.
Why don't we go to the park?
What do you want to do this weekend?
Let's go shopping and then get a coffee.
You know, I hate shopping.
Why don't we go to the park?
4. Morning, have a seat please.
What's the problem?
My stomach hurts.
When did you start to feel like this?
This morning. Maybe I had too much ice cream last night.
Morning, have a seat please.
What's the problem?
My stomach hurts.
When did you start to feel like this?
morning. Maybe I had too much ice cream last night.
Did you have a good time last Sunday,
No. What happened?
Well, we went climbing, but it started to rain halfway, and we got wet all over, so
we had to go back and stay in the hotel.
It was very boring.
Did you have a good time last Sunday, Sam?
No. What happened?
Well, we went climbing, but it started to rain halfway, and we got wet all over, so
we had to go back and stay in the hotel.
It was very boring.
第二节，听下面几段对话或独白。
每段。
对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
B, and What are you going to order, Maria?
三个选项中选出最佳答案。
每段对话或独白读两遍
听下面一段对话，回答第六至第七
两个小题。
I'm thinking about the tomato soup.
How about you, Michael?
George told me a corn salad is really good.
I will order that.
Oh, great. Do you want to share the main course?
sounds great. Shall we have Chinese chicken and rice?
That's okay. What are you going to order, Maria?
I'm thinking about the tomato soup.
How about you, Michael?
George told me a corn salad is really good.
I will order that.
Oh, great. Do you want to share the main course?
That sounds great.
Shall we have Chinese chicken and rice?
That's What time does the next train to leave?
听下面一段对话，回答第八。
第九两个小题。
At 16.35.
Is it a direct train to London?
No. You have two train trains at Birmingham.
I see. Two tickets to London, please.
Single or return, madam?
Single. How much should I pay?
64 pounds. Okay.
Here you are.
time does the next train to leave?
At 16.35.
Is it a direct train to London?
No. You have two train trains at Birmingham.
I see. tickets to London, please.
or return, madam?
Single. How much should I pay?
64 pounds. Okay.
Here you are.
听下面一段独白，回答第十至第十二三个小题。
really don't know why fishing is so popular.
It seems to be one of the best loved hobbies all over the world.
Anywhere there's a river, a lake, or sea, you see people fishing.
I've only fished twice, and I thought it was boring.
I didn't catch any fish.
To me, sitting next to a river waiting for something to happen is strange.
I know lots of people who love fishing.
They even get up at four o in the morning in the winter to sit in the cold.
They say the best time to fish is before the sun comes up.
I say they are crazy.
I really don't know why fishing is so popular.
It seems to be one of the best loved hobbies all over the world.
Anywhere there's a river, a lake, or sea, you see people fishing.
I've only fished twice, and I thought it was boring.
I didn't catch any fish.
To me, sitting next to a river waiting for something to happen is strange.
I know lots of people who love fishing.
They even get up at four o in the morning in the winter to sit in the cold.
They say the best time to fish is before the sun comes up.
I say they are crazy.
听下面一段对话，回答第。
十三至第十五三个小题。
So, what do you like to do for fun?
I like to go to the movies.
So do I.
What movies do you like the most?
I only like cartoons.
Well, that's great.
It's nice that we have something in common.
When do you go to the movies?
I usually go in my free time on weekends.
How about you?
The movie theater is always so crowded on weekends.
I like to go to the movies with my sister during the weekdays.
That's true. And sometimes the tickets are cheaper during that time as well.
What else do you like to do?
I love traveling and playing volleyball.
What about you?
I only like reading books.
So, what do you like to do for fun?
I like to go to the movies.
So do I.
What movies do you like the most?
I only like cartoons.
Well, that's great.
It's nice that we have something in common.
When do you go to the movies?
I usually go in my free time on weekends.
How about you?
The movie theater is always so crowded on weekends.
I like to go to the movies with my sister during the weekdays.
That's true. And sometimes the tickets are cheaper during that time as well.
What else do you like to do?
I love traveling and playing volleyball.
What about you?
I only like reading books.
3. On the first day we got there, we played volleyball on the beach.
第三节：听下面一篇短文，
按照你所听内容的先后顺序。
句将下列图片排序。
短文读两遍。
It was exciting.
The next morning we wanted to visit a village, but it was very rainy and windy.
So we visited the art museum.
Seeing a lot of famous paintings was also quite interesting.
On that afternoon we found that the sun came out.
So we decided to play in the sand on the beach.
On the third day we went boating on the famous lake.
We quickly got the tickets because we had to book them online.
On the last day we were quite tired and came home by bus.
What a great trip we had!
I recently had a holiday trip with my friends to Florida.
On the first day we got there, we played volleyball on the beach.
It was exciting.
The next morning we wanted to visit a village, but it was very rainy and windy.
So we visited the art museum.
Seeing a lot of famous paintings was also quite interesting.
On that afternoon we found that the sun came out.
So we decided to play in sand on the beach.
On the third day we went boating on the famous lake.
We quickly got the tickets because we had book them online.
On the last day we were quite tired and came home by bus.
What a great trip we had!
This is
听力考试到此结束。